NYSUT Vice President's office files. 6174/002
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- U.S. Constitution Bicentennial. See: Bicentennial
- United Federation of Teachers 1986-1995 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  Surveys of members, 1986 and 1995; NYSUT Special Report by secretary-treasurer, re support to UFT and from AFT, August 5, 1994; flyer re election of chapter leaders and delegates, 1988; spring conference speech by Sandra Feldman, president, UFT, May 7, 1988; correspondence between Cortese and president of Yorktown Heights BOCES staff association re potential job loss to pre-K special education teachers, November-December 1987; booklet. "All I Need Is a Chance," highlighting UFT projects, with cover note from Sandra Feldman, September 1, 1987; booklet by AFL-CIO Trade Union Leadership Institute, NYC Central Labor Council, "How Unions Help Your Family," 1986; anti-drug brochure for parents, with press release by UFT, October 28, 1986; handbook, "You and the UFT," n.d., c. 1986; catalog with order forms, "Teacher's Choice Instructional Supplies Program," fall 1986; letter from Cortese congratulating Sandra Feldman on election as president of AFT, January 10, 1986
- UFT Transfer Plan 1994 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  Tentative agreement 5/6/94, as ratified by the Executive Board 5/24/94, "SBO Transfer and Staffing Plan," authorizing certain specialized schools to hire their own teachers; personnel memorandum No. 45, 1993-94, NYC Board of Education, re School-Based Option Transfer and Staffing Plan, May 19, 1994
- UNA-USA Meeting-Strategy 6/5/86, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  United Nations Association of the United States memo re U.N. in financial crisis, March 7, 1986; memo to Al Shanker from NYSUT vp Antonia Cortese reporting on meeting to pressure Congress to meet its financial obligations to the U.N., June 13, 1986; agenda and official meeting description
- UN Association Luncheon 4/30/85, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  Notice of annual meeting; report of the 1983 Convention of the United Nations Association of the United States
- US Constitution Bicentennial. See: Bicentennial
- Values Education. See: Moral Education
- Variances 1993-1995 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  State Education Department memo to principals and superintendents re revised variance process allowing curriculum deviation from Commissioner's Regulations, listing specific requests granted; December 1994; memo for December 1993; NYSUT memo re problem with a variance granted for Madison-Oneida BOCES in that the union rep was not consulted, August 29, 1994
- Vending Machines. See: Pouring Rights
- Violence. See: School Violence
- Vision 1994 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  Preliminary report by State of New York Legislative Commission on Rural Resources, "NY's K-12 Public Education in the 21st Century: A Framework for Action: Proceedings of the 'Vision 21' Education Symposium, January 12-14, 1994, with press release, April 1994; commission overview, including enabling legislation, list of commission members from NYS Senate and Assembly, policy subjects and work program, map and list of NY rural counties, list of bills proposed or enacted into law; letter to Cortese from commission chair, Sen. Charles D. Cook, inviting her to hearings, November 15, 1994
- Vision 21 January 12-14, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  Description of symposium; NYSUT memo re participation; related materials
- Vocational Training. See: State Steering Committee on Regents Policy on Preparation for Postsecondary Education and/or Employment; See: Career and Technical Education
- Welfare Reform 1997 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  NYSUT memo re possible points to include in a position statement on welfare reform, based on recommendations of NYS AFL-CIO and State Education Department, re including education-related activities in satisfying work requirement for welfare recipients
- Whittle Communications (Channel 1) 1993 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  Institute for Social Research (University of Michigan) evaluation of divergent effectiveness of current-events broadcasting across a range of schools, May 14, 1993; letters from Cortese to members of the Board of Regents and Chancellor Carballada, urging that they continue to ban the broadcast in New York schools, noting advertising component, shallowness of news, June 24
- Widmeyer Group Communications Report 12/19/00, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  "A Communications Report for NYSUT," December 6, 2000; phone survey analysis, November 2000
- Widmeyer Contract & Bills 2000 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  Consulting agreement between NYSUT and Widmeyer Communications, September 12, 2000; invoices
- Widmeyer-Baker. Proposal 8/10/00, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  Project proposal for NYSUT communications audit; list of clients
- Widmeyer Group Communications Audit (RFP) 2000 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  Request for proposals to Widmeyer and other public relations firms (Eric Mower and Harger, Sharp) for NYSUT communications audit; NYSUT memo proposing enhanced Internet services for members
- Widmeyer 10/2/00, 2000 (Box 33, Folder 21)
  Confidential memo to Cortese re NYSUT communications needs, August 17, 2000; memo on retiree health insurance and report on NYSUT Retiree Medical Costs, "Examining Future Costs and Funding," presented to NYSUT officers and associates, August 27, 2000
- (Widmeyer) Hager Sharp. Communications Audit 2000 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  Project proposal to NYSUT, June 2000; "Internal Communications Audit: Findings, Conclusions & Recommendations for the American Federation of Teachers," by Hager Sharp Inc., October 1997
- Women. See: AFT Joint Civil, Human and Women's Rights Committee; See also: Revolutionary Women, 2000
- Women's Issues. Comparable Worth/Pay Equity (folder 1 of 2) 1985 (Box 33, Folder 23)
  Correspondence re pay equity from school secretaries association and others; statement by AL-CIO Executive Council on pay equity, February 23, 1984; SEIU Pay Equity Issues Packet, n.d; printed articles and newspaper clippings. See also: Teacher Compensation
- Women's Issues. Comparable Worth/Pay Equity (folder 2 of 2) 1982-1985 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  Statement of Thomas R. Donohue, secretary-treasurer, AFL-CIO, before the Subcommittees on Civil Service, Compensation and Employee Benefits and Human Resources of the House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service on pay equity and comparable worth, September 21, 1982; statement of AFT to subcommittees, September 16, 1982; summary of legal decision, AFSCME et al. v. State of Washington et al. (C82-465T), December 20, 1983; paper, "Fighting Wage Discrimination: An outline of discriminatory practices, substantive law and organizational issues," by Winn Newman and Lisa Newell; report by National Commission on Working Women, "Women's Work: Undervalued, Underpaid," July 1982; "Pay Equity Issues," report prepared by SEIU for the Southern California Comparable Worth Coalition, April 1982
- Women's Issues. Comparable Worth Meeting 8/16/85, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 25)
  Correspondence; resolutions
- Workplace Literacy 1990 (Box 33, Folder 26)
  AFL-CIO Human Resources Development Institute manual, "Worker-Centered Learning: A Union Guide to Workplace Literacy," 1990
- World Cocoa Foundation 2004 (Box 33, Folder 27)
  Materials re Sustainable Tree Crops Program; letter to Cortese from Chocolate Manufacturers Association, April 2004; article in New York Teacher, "Schools can help end child slavery on cocoa farms," October 22, 2003
- Year Round Schooling 1996-1997 (Box 33, Folder 28)
  Materials arguing against year-round schooling; summary of experience of schools that tried it, including financial costs and community reactions
- York State Manor 1990-1997 (Box 33, Folder 29)
  Brochures and correspondence re residence for retired teachers of NYS
- York State Manor 1991-1994 (Box 33, Folder 30)
  Investment policy guidelines; charter and amendments; request for review of operations, November 18, 1994; findings of on-site visit by Ernst & Young, noting need to update admissions assumptions in light of changes in patterns of adult care, September 27, 1993; report by Ernst & Young re liability exposure, August 8, 1994; letter from Ernst & Young re long-term strategic plan for facility, June 27, 1994
- York State Manor 1994 (Box 33, Folder 31)
  Facility evaluation report, August 8, 1994; appendix of photographs; summary report of physical renovation recommendations, September 19, 1994; drafts
- York State Manor 1994 (Box 33, Folder 32)
  Ernst & Young draft review; resident profiles; correspondence
- York State Manor 1996-1999, 1995-1999 (Box 33, Folder 33)
  Correspondence re sale of facility to Health Care Associates (HCA), 1999; notice to residents of closure, March 20, 1996
- York State Manor 10/15/92, 1992 (Box 33, Folder 34)
  Operating budget; handwritten notes
- York State Manor 8/9/94, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 35)
  Correspondence re meeting at facility to review recommendations; handwritten notes
- York State Manor 5/17/95, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 36)
  Brochure for James Square Pavilion Adult Residence; handwritten notes
- York State Manor 4/4/95, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 37)
  Letter to residents outlining operating challenges, changes in market, plans to sell the facility, April 4, 1995; schedule of meeting by NYSUT officials at facility; handwritten notes
- York State Manor Meeting 1/6/94, 1994 (Box 33, Folder 38)
  List of trustees; memo from Cortese to NYSUT Board of Directors updating them re York State Manor